<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://macredd.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://macredd.in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-16T15:45:45-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mac Reddin</title><subtitle>Mac Reddin. Product, design, startups and tea.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How We’re Building The Club Fund</title><link href="https://macredd.in/how-were-building-the-club-fund" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How We're Building The Club Fund" /><published>2020-09-16T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-16T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/how-were-building-the-club-fund</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/how-were-building-the-club-fund">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;max-width: 180px&quot; src=&quot;../images/sticker-fund_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago we announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.community.club/fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Community Club Fund&lt;/a&gt; (The Club Fund), an investment fund dedicated to investing in the future of community through community-drive companies, infrastructure and tools. TL;DR of the fund:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We look for products and tools that will improve how communities are built, grown, and engaged&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We invest $25k-50k at seed, pre-seed or even earlier. We don’t need anyone else to be ‘in first’, we’re happy to be your first check.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re investing globally (yes, really!); we believe talent is universal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every new fund talks about how they’re ‘different’, but the vast majority simply continue the current status quo. Rather than just saying that the Club Fund is different, we’re laying it all out. We’re not just building a fund, we’re building a community for the future of community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;by-community-for-community&quot;&gt;By Community, For Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not professional investors — we are community builders, backed by community professionals, who are investing in the future of community. Community-driven companies are the future, and they’ll need new tooling and infrastructure to maximize their success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we’re creating the Community Council — a group of top community leaders across various industries that can help companies building great community products. The council members are (financially and emotionally) invested in the future of community and tooling, which means that when The Club invests in your company, all of these experts are on your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Community Council is made up of the LPs and advisors to the fund. They’ll be a part of our investment process with full access to our deal flow and the ability to provide their thoughts and feedback on any company we’re looking at. We’ll be announcing the founding members of the council when the fund officially launches on October 1st!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transparency&quot;&gt;Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venture capital has traditionally been an incredibly opaque industry, but hey, we’re not professional investors so we can throw those games right out the window! We’re here to help people build great communities, tools, and products, and we’re going to do it transparently. This means we’ll be sharing our Community Council, our LPs, and our investment memos with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means we’re sharing companies we come across with other interested investors — we won’t be playing those games of hiding deals in order to win them for fear of them being ‘stolen’ by other investors. We want to make sure founders are working with the right investors for them, and if that isn’t us, then that’s ok!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in being part of our bi-weekly deal flow memo? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mac@commsor.com&quot;&gt;Shoot me an email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commsor-pool&quot;&gt;Commsor Pool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty common (if not the norm these days) for founders to become investors as their companies grow, either as angels or through a proper fund. That’s always felt weird to us — founders leveraging the success and work of their teams to give themselves more options. But we wanted to do something different with The Club Fund, and that’s why we’re structuring the carry to be shared amongst the full Commsor team; the people who help make the Community Club possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each quarter, half of the fund carry (any profits the fund makes) will be granted to those who are working at Commsor during that quarter. When companies in the Club Fund are successful, the whole team will benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope the rest of the industry takes this to heart — founders raising funds, you should keep in mind who helped you get your startups to where they are now. Make a commitment to the futures of your team, and give them a chance to be involved in the potentially life changing results of investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optionality-for-founders&quot;&gt;Optionality for Founders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAFE notes have been the standard for early stage investments for quite a while now, but they aren’t always what’s best for founders. To address this, we’re creating a brand new funding instrument and we will be sharing more details about it in the weeks to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-commitments&quot;&gt;Initial Commitments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already committed to a number of great companies which will be included in the first quarter of the fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toucan.events/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toucan&lt;/a&gt; - rethinking video for virtual social events. Founded by a brother-sister team, we’ve already been using them for our community happy hour events!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zebraiq.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ZebraIQ&lt;/a&gt; - The ultimate community tool for creators and celebrities. Incredible team working on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startplaying.games/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;StartPlaying.Games&lt;/a&gt; - Y Combinator S20 graduate, creating the infrastructure for the tabletop gaming community. Our inner nerds loved it the moment we saw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 other companies that are yet to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Club exists because we want to see more cool shit exist in the community space. Interested in helping us make this happen? &lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/v/back/the-club&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Become an LP via AngelList&lt;/a&gt; and join the Community Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for funding from The Club? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.community.club/fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apply here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slack as a Community Platform</title><link href="https://macredd.in/slack-as-a-community-platform" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slack as a Community Platform" /><published>2020-09-07T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-07T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/slack-as-a-community-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/slack-as-a-community-platform">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why would you pick Slack over a forum platform for your community?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Should I go with Slack or Discourse for the community that I’m building?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You can’t build a community on Slack.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked some form of these questions almost daily. The Slack vs forum debate is one that burns eternally amongst community builders, with strong supporters on either side. But it’s a debate without an answer, because there is no answer. Slack and forums are fundamentally different tools, with different core structures, designed for different purposes. You can’t compare the two, nor should you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-love-slack-as-a-community-platform&quot;&gt;Why I love Slack as a community platform&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We run the Community Club on Slack, and have no plans to switch off any time soon. A few reasons why I am bullish on Slack (or Slack-like platforms) sticking around for community for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy setup &amp;amp; no cost&lt;/strong&gt; . You can easily spin it up and launch your community in less than a day on Slack. You won’t need a dedicated person to manage it, or months of setup work. And assuming you go with the free tier, it won’t cost you a cent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low barrier to engage.&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on your target audience, Slack is likely something many of them are using every day for work, so it’s very low effort for them to join and participate. Unlike forums, which require you to be intentional about visiting them and engaging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat is better than forum posts&lt;/strong&gt;. This is very dependent on the type of community you’re trying to build. The nature of conversation tends to be different than forums. Chat allows for shorter, more casual messaging, while on forums you tend to have to be more intentional (for lack of a better word).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-cant-compare-slack-to-forums&quot;&gt;You can’t compare Slack to forums&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is not a forum, and forums are not Slack. Slack is chat-based and forums are thread and post based. The type of conversation that happens on Slack is completely different than what happens on forums. I’m not even sure if you can call forum posts a ‘conversation’ like you can with Slack chats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big gripes with Slack is the message limit, the fact that (on the free tier at least), you’re capped at 10,000 messages before the history starts becoming unsearchable. While most consider it a drawback to Slack, I consider it one if its best features as a community platform. There, I’ve said the unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/slack-message-limit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack message limit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of image is often used to point to one of Slack’s biggest weaknesses. You can’t search these 155k messages on the free tier, they’re ‘lost’ and it would be better if these messages were on a forum that was searchable. But I’d argue that most of the 155k messages wouldn’t even have happened on a forum, because the nature of conversation is completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major use case for permanence is to prevent the same topic being talked about multiple times. Why have a new conversation when you can just refer to something someone posted 6 months ago? For starters, this happens on forums anyways, even though history is searchable and permanent. How often do you see a new thread on a forum closed by a moderator and then linking out to an old thread?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what is &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; with forums. This style of conversation and management actually surpresses conversation from newcomers. “Oh people have already talked about this before, no need for me to add my voice to the conversation”. The ephemeral nature of chat actually encourages more and newer voices to contribute. There’s a serendipitous nature to chat-based conversation vs forum threads. You can write, enter, read, and respond all in one continuous thought process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is best compared to platforms like Discord, Telegram and WhatsApp, not forums. Many of the best communities I know find ways to combine an ephermal chat solution with a more permanent forum solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slack-isnt-for-you-if&quot;&gt;Slack isn’t for you if…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; from perfect as a community platform. I mean, its not even meant to be one! For certain types of communities, it can be a killer choice, but it certainly isn’t for every community. Slack probably isn’t a great choice for you if:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your audience isn’t likely to already be on Slack. In this case you lose the benefit of the lower barrier to entry and participation that other communities get from having their members already be on Slack for work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your community is large, more than 5k-10k members. While there are examples of successful Slack communities with 20k+ members, Slack really starts to fall apart around the few thousand member mark. You’ll eat through the 10,000 message limit too fast, conversation will flow faster than anyone can follow, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You absolutely need permanence. If your commuity is being built as a knowledge-sharing or support-community, a forum platform might be better for you. Can you imagine StackOverflow as a chat-based community? Absolutely not. They need the permanence and searchability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen many companies actually roll with Slack + a forum-based solution to great success. You need to start with your purpose and community goals before deciding on a platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slack-should-support-community&quot;&gt;Slack should support community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is built for work. In their own words “Slack is where work happens”, and their stock ticker is $WORK. They’ve clearly not built the platform for communities, and it lacks features that we’ve come to expect as standard elsewhere - permanance, moderation tools, analytics, etc. But what do all these features have in common? They’re primarily built for the community manager, not the community member!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to fall into this trap of looking at tools from a management perspective. The tools are, after all, designed with you as the buyer in mind. Your community member isn’t buying the tool, so the features that are pushed are all about the benefit to you as a community manager. But community is about the members, their experience, and the value they get out of it. Don’t forget about the community member when making your platform choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly feel that Slack should lean into the grassroots community usage that has sprung up on their platform over the past five years. Many communities exist on Slack because people were already on it for work, and by supporting communities more intentionally Slack will be better able to keep people within their ecosystem for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is Slack the best platform for your community? Maybe - it depends on so many factors. At the end of the day, discussing platforms is the community equivalent of picking the right language for software development. In the short term, it probably doesn’t matter. Pick something, understand the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, and just start building your community. You can always switch platforms when you have a reason to. Don’t be frozen by platform paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if you think its not possible to build a succesful community on Slack, I suggest you check out our community, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.community.club/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Community Club&lt;/a&gt;. We’re nearly 1,500 members, run on Slack, and going strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ColinBrauns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LaimaVai&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Laima&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/karl_mc_carthy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Karl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexjpanagis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt; and many others from the Community Club for talking about this subject and inspiring me to write this post!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“Why would you pick Slack over a forum platform for your community?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Predictions for Community in the 2020s</title><link href="https://macredd.in/2020-community-predictions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Predictions for Community in the 2020s" /><published>2020-08-27T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/2020-community-predictions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/2020-community-predictions">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software is eating the world, and community is eating software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no particular order, a few predictions for community in the 2020s. A thread 🧵&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;💪 Community will continue to be a broad term, but finally people and companies will fully grasp that an audience does not mean the same thing as a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🪑 Community will finally get a seat at the table, following in the footsteps of customer success from a decade ago. Community will become its own department within orgs, leading to more Heads of Community, Chief Community Officers, and other community leadership roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✨ Continued specialization of roles in community. Community Manager will turn into Community Engagement, Community Marketing, Community Support, Community Success, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🙋 And then we’ll see other roles start to merge under community. Community, customer support, and customer success will overlap and start to blend together. Traditional CS roles will still exist, but more ‘low-level’ support will be offloaded to communities and community teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;💼 The unbundling of LinkedIn. What Dribbble is to designers, we’ll see for nurses, marketers, community managers, and every other career vertical, providing community, ‘portfolios’, and better job hunting experiences tailored to the specific type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🎁 The unbundling of Reddit. Every subreddit will get its own dedicated community app, built specifically to serve the unique needs of that vertical. Vertical specificity will win out over general community platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚗 Community-driven versions of existing products and services will continue to be built, eventually taking over those who built without community. See Public vs Robinhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 Interactive audio and audio communities will continue to grow. Spotify will enter the market with their own offering, or acquire an existing player similarly to when they initially entered podcasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🕺 We’ll see innovation in the community platform space. Everything right now looks like some form of forum or ‘Slack for community’. We’ll see platforms that rethink the idea of community from the ground up, in less structured ways than ‘forums’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🌍 The explosion of remote work will continue to drive a greater need for community at every level, online and offline, locally and globally. Expect more companies to build verticals in Nextdoor’s space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🤑 Companies will continue to acquire communities as starting points for their own. See Outreach + Saleshacker, Stripe + Indiehackers, and DigitalOcean + Scotch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;💡 More and more companies will build communities of interest, rather than just customer &amp;amp; support communities. This will enable their communities to reach a wider audience, and ultimately be seen as revenue generators rather than cost centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;💬 A number of independent communities will turn into full-fledged businesses and media ‘empires’ as they grow beyond the community they started with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🛠 Consolidation of tools. We’re currently in a golden age of community, engagement and event tools, but over the next decade we’ll see major players start to lead, acquire competitors, and ultimately ‘win’. We’ll also see existing companies (Salesforce, Slack, etc) invest more in community by acquiring companies that are being built right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🙊 Increased innovation will occur in the moderation space. As community gets elevated in organizations, companies will finally want to invest in tools to help make moderation easier and less dependent on pure manpower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🏢 Companies will treat their internal teams more like communities, and there will be an expansion of internal community teams, especially at cos with 1,000+ employees. Remote-first companies will set this trend, needing to be more intentional about fostering internal community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;👋 Continued normalization of internet friends, people that you met in online communities rather than in-person. This has been normal for a decade or more in the gaming world, but it will bleed over to professional friends and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🏃‍♀️ In-person events will come back quickly post-Covid, but they will be smaller and more intimate, focusing on genuine connection. It will be a while before we see large 500+ person events and conferences again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📆 Companies will continue to invest in online events and engagement as they realize how much larger of a reach they can achieve for lower cost and overhead. In-person conferences will adopt hybrid models, offering virtual access in addition to their physical locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any predictions of your own for how community (especially within organizations) will evolve over the next decade? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theteaguns&quot;&gt;Let me know!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Software is eating the world, and community is eating software</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating Culture in a Remote Team</title><link href="https://macredd.in/creating-cuture-in-a-remote-team" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating Culture in a Remote Team" /><published>2020-07-12T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/creating-cuture-in-a-remote-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/creating-cuture-in-a-remote-team">&lt;p&gt;Remote work is the future, at least for tech startups. Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; (each with 100s of employees) have proven that it is totally possible to build a successful behemoth of a company without forcing everyone into an office in San Fransisco or New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While being remote-first does have &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chris_herd/status/1281945096020254720?s=20&quot;&gt;an incredible number of advantages&lt;/a&gt; over being office-first, building culture can be a challenge. Culture is something that remote teams have to actively think about and approach more intentionally than non-remote teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your idea of remote culture is Zoom happy hours (even worse if you make them mandatory – how dare you!), then you’ve already lost the culture game. I’ve worked remote for nearly a decade – both building teams and working within teams – and while I don’t claim to have all the answers, here are some of the things we do at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commsor.com/&quot;&gt;Commsor&lt;/a&gt; to foster a culture and build the company that we all dream of working at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;define-how-you-work&quot;&gt;Define how you work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture isn’t just the non-work things that your team does, it is also how your team communicates, collaborates, and ultimately builds the business together. How much work you do, how you plan and make decisions, how the team communicates when things go well, and how your team recovers when things don’t go well. This creates the foundation for your culture. You can’t slap events, emojis and some GIFs on top of a shitty workplace and expect to build a great team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trust-your-team&quot;&gt;Trust your team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust your team. That’s it. Trust is important in all forms of relationships, work or personal, but its absolutely critical in remote teams because you simply have no choice. Remote work is a micromanager’s worst nightmare and there should be no place in your team for such a management style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over-communicating, not assuming, and sharing progress on projects will go a long way towards building a foundation of trust. At Commsor we encourage everyone to share half-baked work rather than waiting for something to be perfectly polished. This also has the added benefit of enabling the team to provide feedback and input earlier in projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;establish-a-casual-check-in-and-check-out&quot;&gt;Establish a casual check-in and check-out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning when I log into Slack, I’m greeted by three good morning messages from our teammates in the EU (5+ hours ahead of me), and then I add the fourth good morning. Similarly, we often say goodbye when logging off for the day. Not only is saying good morning and goodbye a nice thing to do, it also serves to let the team know when you’re around and working, allowing a strong asynchronous style of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t make these check-ins required, and don’t build structure around it (no logging times in a spreadsheet, otherwise you’re already a lost cause). Just let your team organically greet and say farewell to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/culture-trust.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of a 'check-out' in our Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-time-and-space-for-non-work-things&quot;&gt;Create time and space for non-work things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t force your team to attend ‘social events’ (you probably shouldn’t be forcing them to do anything anyways), but do provide the space and time for them to interact with other teammates about personal things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Commsor, these spaces come in a variety of forms. We have dedicated non-work channels, including #tea-room (our version of our virtual watercooler), #reading (for sharing interesting books, tweets, articles), #music (an endless stream of great music), where the team is encouraged to share and discuss fun things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a bi-weekly game “night” (with purposeful quotation around the word “night” because it ends up being a game late-morning for some of us due to timezones). This is totally optional, but allows members of the team to get together, play some games together, socialize and bond over non-work fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/culture-tshirt.png&quot; alt=&quot;John with his new shirt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/culture-tshirt2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Discussion about our pivot to a fashion business&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one of our recent game nights we played a Jackbox game called Tee K.O., where you have to create t-shirt designs and pair them with text from other players. It’s way more fun than it sounds, I promise! John ended up buying the winning design from the game as a real t-shirt, and if that isn’t culture, I don’t know what is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;culture-add-not-culture-fit&quot;&gt;Culture-add, not culture-fit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often have you heard that a company is looking for someone that is a ‘culture-fit’ to their existing team? One of the biggest advantages of a remote team is the access to a wider, more global, more diverse talent pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our team, every member has brought additions to how we work and interact as a team, some small, some large. Tomek started sharing what he was having for lunch, and now the team loves chatting about the great food their eating. John started sharing what music he was listening to, and now we have a dedicated #music channel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture-add is how you build a diverse team. Hire people that will add to and improve your existing culture, not fit into some cookie cutter personality. You’re building a company, not a cult (unless you’re WeWork, but we all know how that’s worked out). Culture isn’t a top-down thing, designed to be set and led by a single person. Your team is your culture, empower them to help define and shape it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-retreats&quot;&gt;Team retreats&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is currently 7, yet I’ve only met 2 of them face to face. While I certainly get a lot of virtual face time with them, in-person face time is still important and critical to really getting to know your teammates. While we haven’t been able to have a team retreat yet, we are planning on getting the team together in early 2021 (please wear a mask so I can finally meet the rest of our awesome team!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more tactical thoughts, I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/learn/remote-work/how-run-company-retreat-remote-team/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; from Wade Foster about how they run team retreats at Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While our culture at Commsor is ever-evolving, and far from perfect, I do think that actively thinking about and nurturing it from day one will prove to be critical as our team continues to grow. It’s never too early to start thinking about the culture and team you want to build, especially as a remote-first company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Remote work is the future, at least for tech startups. Companies like Zapier and Invision (each with 100s of employees) have proven that it is totally possible to build a successful behemoth of a company without forcing everyone into an office in San Fransisco or New York City.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Things Startups Can Do to Gain a Competitive Edge in 2020</title><link href="https://macredd.in/4-things-startups-can-do-to-gain-a-competitive-edge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Things Startups Can Do to Gain a Competitive Edge in 2020" /><published>2020-02-18T04:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T04:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/4-things-startups-can-do-to-gain-a-competitive-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/4-things-startups-can-do-to-gain-a-competitive-edge">&lt;p&gt;It can be daunting starting a business, especially in the tech world where you’re often trying to displace an existing giant to some degree. Startups have long had the advantage of being leaner, faster moving, and more responsive than their older and larger competition, but there are always other ways that you can gain a competitive edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four things that we’ve adopted (some intentional, some not) at Commsor that other early stage startups can use to their advantage right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being remote&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leveraging the ‘human touch’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopting no code tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;being-remote&quot;&gt;Being Remote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With access to tools like Slack, Github, Clubhouse and more, collaborating with people all over the world has never been easier. There are definitely unique challenges that come with building a remote-first company (with startups building explicitly for these challenges as I write this) – but the benefits for an early stage startup hugely outweigh the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding exceptional, diverse and driven teammates is critical to the success of any startup, and founders often state that recruiting good talent is one of their biggest pain points. A company like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commsor.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Commsor&lt;/a&gt; could never compete with the likes of Google and Facebook hiring in New York City or San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are talented people all over the world, and being remote-first has enabled us to hire incredible teammates that we would never have access to if we’d stuck with the talent pool in and around NYC. Not only is the global talent pool vastly larger than your local one, its also more diverse. Hiring people from other states and countries brings new perspectives on life and the world to your business and team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a startup is all about making every dollar count, maximizing your runway, and surviving to success. If you’re headquartered in a major US urban center, hiring locally is really expensive (and not just from a salary perspective). In NYC for example, office space costs an  average of $14,800 per employee annually (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketwatch.com/story/heres-how-much-your-company-pays-to-rent-office-space-2015-05-27&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bigger talent pool, easier time attracting talent, and less expensive. Being remote is a no-brainer, and I haven’t even touched on all the other benefits of remote work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ever growing community of remote leaders is insanely awesome and supportive, so you can easily find others to help you overcome the remote-first challenges. A few people you should follow on Twitter if you’re interested in learning more about building remote teams:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chris_herd&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris Herd&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Jobvo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Job van der Voort&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andreasklinger&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andreas Klinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have any additional recommendations for people who share insight into building remote teams? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theteaguns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Let me know!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leveraging-the-human-touch&quot;&gt;Leveraging the ‘Human Touch’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Do things that don’t scale&lt;/a&gt;’ is one of the most repeated pieces of startup advice that I hear. Probably because it’s true. The larger a company gets, the fewer chances it has to do things that don’t scale, and maintain that ‘human touch’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early stage startups that take advantage of this will have a clear way to stand above the crowd. Only startups can do things like having the CEO get on the phone to make a sale, or sending a personalized email (and I mean actually personalized, not just automated and designed to look like it’s from the founder) to each new sign up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do things that your competitors physically &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; because of their scale. Fill the feature gaps in your product with manual work, find your first customers in the unscalable and inefficient channels that larger companies tend to ignore. Don’t advertise on Google or Facebook – you won’t be at a scale where it matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obsess over getting your first handful of customers, and then turn them into your best marketing channel by obsessing even more over making them happy with your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read the Paul Graham essay linked above, make that your first stop after reading this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-community&quot;&gt;Creating Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start building a community around and for your business right now. Regardless of what stage you’re at, community, if done correctly, can be the single most impactful moat you can build. Community unlocks the power of your customer network, enabling you to scale yourself, your resources, and your presence in ways not possible on traditional social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to invest thousands of dollars or hundreds of hours of time to get started with community. For B2B or developer centric businesses, just spin up a free Slack channel and go! Some of the benefits of building a community:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier access to user research&lt;/strong&gt; - Have you ever tried to send a user survey via email, maybe tried to entice people with a $5 Amazon gift card to give you product feedback? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many-to-many relationships&lt;/strong&gt; - On ‘follower-based’ social media like Twitter, your existing followers don’t benefit from a new follower. With a ‘many-to-many’ community, each new member increases the value for existing members, bringing new content and engagement. As your community grows, you’ll be able to depend on members to engage each other more and more, requiring less and less direct input and work from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Providing a strong support + success channel&lt;/strong&gt; - Old and boring: asking customers to email you and wait 24 to forever hours for a reply. New and exciting: empowering your customers to help each other, and get more direct access to your success and support functions through community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community as a feature&lt;/strong&gt; - Community can even be a feature for your business, especially if its something your competitors don’t have. Which product, all other things equal, would you rather buy from? The one without a community, or the one with a community where you can connect with other users, get direct support from the company, etc?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many more reasons you should be building a community alongside your startup. More on that in a future post! If you want to learn more right now, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://comm.chat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;join Community Chat&lt;/a&gt;, a community for community builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-code-no-problem&quot;&gt;No Code? No Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The golden age of no code is upon us. You no longer need programming experience or a technical cofounder, or lots of $$ and months of work to build an idea, bring it to 
market, and begin to validate it. You can go from idea to some form of launch within a few days, sometimes even hours thanks to tools like Airtable, Notion, Zapier, Webflow and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of Commsor (then called CommSponsor) was built in just 3 hours, without writing a single line of code. Was the product perfect? Definitely not. Calling it a product might even be a bit generous. But it let us launch, get feedback, and decide it was worth dedicating more resources to. It unlocked the future of what Commsor would eventually become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No code might enable you to launch version one of your product, or a new feature you want to test it, or it might help you speed up an internal process. Regardless, the right no code tools used in the right way can enable you to build faster and for less money. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makerpad.co/stories&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;tons of great stories&lt;/a&gt; of businesses of every size using no code tools in all sorts of ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend checking out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makerpad.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Makerpad&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking to start learning more about no code tools and how you can use them at your startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting, building and growing a successful business will always be difficult, but it’s never been easier to get started. Use the tools and processes available to you to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build remote to access a wider pool of talent while saving money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be obsessed with your customers, giving them the support, success, and human level of support that larger companies simply can’t&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a community for your target customers. Bring them together, build trust and give them value beyond your product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage the growing world of no code tools to build faster and cheaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It can be daunting starting a business, especially in the tech world where you’re often trying to displace an existing giant to some degree. Startups have long had the advantage of being leaner, faster moving, and more responsive than their older and larger competition, but there are always other ways that you can gain a competitive edge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Minecraft Taught Me About Community</title><link href="https://macredd.in/what-minecraft-taught-me-about-community" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Minecraft Taught Me About Community" /><published>2020-02-07T14:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-07T14:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/what-minecraft-taught-me-about-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/what-minecraft-taught-me-about-community">&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service&quot;&gt;an excellent post&lt;/a&gt; by Eugene Wei about Status as a Service earlier this week, I found myself thinking about my past experiences with community and status, and how those experiences could be applied to the communities I was working with today. I set out to write a fairly quick overview, but as you can see below I ended up with something a big longer. Strap in for story time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commsor.com&quot;&gt;Commsor&lt;/a&gt;,  I started and ran a business called The Chunk. Most of you have  probably heard of Minecraft, but I’d bet that most of you aren’t aware  that Minecraft used to support an entire ecosystem of startups (and  still does, to a lesser extent) in the form of Minecraft hosting and  servers. Unlike Triple A games like Call of Duty, Minecraft didn’t  provide centralized multiplayer servers (Realms being the exception, but  that service launched far too late to have a major impact).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This  meant that the entire multiplayer experience was left up to independent  server hosts. The Minecraft multiplayer ecosystem exploded, quickly  growing from small, classic survival servers to custom games built  within the game. Minecraft was becoming a sort of game engine, and I was  one of thousands of people that saw potential in building custom  content on top of such a world wide phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.commsor.com/content/images/2019/11/chunkbanner.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Banner for The Chunk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;a-banner-advert-for-the-chunk&quot;&gt;A banner advert for The Chunk&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so The Chunk was born, a Minecraft server network made up of a  hub world connected to various smaller game servers where players could  play a variety of custom content we’d create for them. This content  ranged from simple capture the flag style games, like BlockWars, to more  complex recreations of AAA titles like Titanfall. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/mod-of-the-week-ironfall-for-minecraft/&quot;&gt;Yes, we recreated a first person shooter game with mechs, rocket launchers and more in Minecraft.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For  the first year of building The Chunk, I thought we were building a  gaming company. We were, after all, creating games, had players, and  measured our success and metrics in much the same way that larger video  game companies do. It wasn’t until the start of our second year that it  really hit me – The Chunk was a community business that just happened to  be a gaming community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of our first year, we  had a variety custom games, tons of micro content, and we held our first  big ‘state of The Chunk’ survey. We wanted to collect feedback from our  players, find out what they liked and how we could improve. One of the core questions in the survey was “What is your favorite game on The  Chunk?”. We had fairly good metrics on which games players spent their  time on, so we figured we roughly knew how that question would be  answered. We were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a bit of a sidebar before I reveal  what the answer was. In order to play games on The Chunk you first had  to join a ‘hub’ server. From the hub server you could form parties, chat  with other players, and join into any of our games to start playing.  Players would often hang out on this hub to chat, find others to play  with and just generally socialize. Nearly 30% of our players answered  the favorite game question with a write in: “The Hub”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d never  treated the hub as a game, and as such hadn’t included it on the list of  favorite game options. In retrospect that result should have been  obvious to me - the games on The Chunk were just a means to socialize,  and the hub was the central location for all that socialization to  happen. Players chatted about their days, game strategies, even met  future significant others on our hub. Players came for the games, but  stayed for the social hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise that my rambling above is mostly necessary backstory so that I  can share what The Chunk and Minecraft taught me about community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.commsor.com/content/images/2019/11/ChunkhubT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Chunk hub&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-of-the-chunk-hub-v3-showing-three-games---minerware-haunted-and-iron-fall&quot;&gt;Part of the Chunk Hub v3, showing three games - Minerware, Haunted and Iron Fall&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earning-social-status-and-social-capital&quot;&gt;Earning Social Status and Social Capital&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running, growing and hosting The Chunk wasn’t free. At our peak we  had a paid and fully remote team of 10 with nearly 50 volunteer player  moderators and hundreds of dollars per month in hosting costs. All our  games and content were free for anyone to access, so we had to find ways  to get some players to give us money - a freemium model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could  have taken the “pay to win” (p2w) approach, where those who spend money  get advantages in the games. Better weapons, better armor, more speed,  etc. Most Minecraft servers took this approach, but we were trying to  build something different, something that was fair for all players,  premium or free.So we turned to social status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players  could purchase a premium rank and get access to a fancy colored name,  special hats pets and other cosmetic items. These cosmetic upgrades  offered no gameplay bonus, they just made players look cool.  And for all the players who saw our hub as their favorite ‘game’,  looking cool and standing out from other players provided social status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This  model has been applied to gaming more and more in the last decade,  especially with games like Fortnite. Fortnite is 100% free to play, and  they monetize exclusively by selling players cool looking skins,  pickaxes and other cosmetic items. Just like on The Chunk, these  cosmetic items offer zero bonuses to gameplay. Yet Fortnite parent  company &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/27/epic-fortnite-3-billion-profit/&quot;&gt;Epic still made $3 billion in profit in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, with estimates attributing more than $2 billion of that to Fortnite. Social status is powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I  can feel you asking “But how does this apply to my community? It’s  completely free and I’m not going to charge any of my members for  anything.” Social status still plays a very important place in a free  community. The most active members who contribute the most will  naturally rise to the top of the somewhat invisible social order of the  community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see this phenomenon on Reddit, where users who  contribute frequent, quality discussion are often recognized and stand  above your regular Reddit readers. A great example of this is u/Unidan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unidan&quot;&gt;who even has his own Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt;! Some community platforms, like Reddit and its’ upvote system, have a built in way for users to rise to the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You  should consider finding ways to recognize the top members in your  community, whether that be rewarding the most active users with a  special role, featuring a user of the month, or something else. Give  community members a way to earn social status and capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;varied-member-experiences&quot;&gt;Varied Member Experiences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of custom games and content at The Chunk, and some  players exclusively played one game while others jumped around across  many games. Hardcore players of Block Wars (our capture the flag game)  had different expectations than players of Thimble (a casual jumping  game). Trying to design, provide for and engage with our players could  never have worked with a ‘one size fits all’ approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same  goes for most communities. Each member of your community will have a  different individual experience, depending on who they interact with in  the community and their purpose for joining. You, as the community  leader, will have an especially unique experience compared to your  average members. Find out who is in your community, why they are there,  and what their differing expectations from the community are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You  likely won’t be able to provide one type of engagement or content and  expect to provide value to all members. You’ll have to break your  community members into buckets and provide value add for each bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take  Latka SaaS Hackers, a Slack community of SaaS (software as a service)  founders, CEOs, investors and professionals. The community consists of  veteran and new founders, investors, and other SaaS professionals  (marketers, product managers, sales and more). They all have different  expectations for the group, so various ways have been designed various  ways for each of these community member buckets to find unique value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For  the more veteran founders, there are private Slack channels where they  can interact with other verified founders at their level. For the less  experienced founders, the community hosts a weekly Ask-Me-Anything  session with a prominent founder, investor or professional, giving them a  chance to learn from those who’ve been there before them. There are  also have channels dedicated to discussing sales for those who are  learning how to be effective at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A community is a composition  of smaller sub-communities. You first need to understood who your  community members are, what buckets they fall into, and then find ways  to provide value to each of those groups of members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-community-engagement&quot;&gt;Create Community Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days of The Chunk, we had problems with low player  counts. At certain times, our total player count would dip too low for  some games to have enough players to start, which created a vicious  cycle. Players who wanted to play a game that didn’t have enough other  players would eventually leave, preventing that game from ever getting  the required number to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To encourage new players to try some  of these games, we started hosting weekly events. These events helped  get existing players into these less popular games, while also  attracting new players to bolster the player count. Something really  interesting happened after we’d been doing these events for a few weeks –  the player counts of the games stayed higher between the events. We  became less and less dependent on the events for success, and were able  to cycle them into other games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll likely face a similar  problem in your community, especially when first starting out. If you  simply put strangers together under the banner of ‘community’, chances  are that you’ll end up with a silent community. Typically, users won’t  be engagement creators as they’ll end up following the 90 - 9 - 1 rule,  which states that in a community only 1% of members will actively create  content and engagement, while 9% will engage with created content. This  leaves 90% as lurkers, who may very well still find value in the  community, even if they aren’t visibly contributing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact  distribution will vary from community to community, but in the early  days you need to be the 1% that creates engagement. Give your members  content to engage with and respond to. This could be as simple as posing  a question of the week or consistently sharing interesting content with  your members. You could also host digital events like we did at The  Chunk. Find out what type of content and events your community engages  best with, and give it to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your community grows, you’ll  reach a critical mass where you have enough members that the 1% creating  content will be more than just you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;let-members-contribute&quot;&gt;Let Members Contribute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At The Chunk, the primary way that we let our members contribute was  through our player moderator system. Anyone who has ever been involved  in gaming in any way will know that gamers can be toxic when left  unsupervised. Our player moderators were made up of the older, more  mature members of our player base, who volunteered their time to help  deal with reports of players breaking rules, bullying, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What  did they get in return for their time? Social status and capital! The  player moderator rank and title was an envious one in game that many  other players respected and looked up to. The little red “Mod” tag that  these volunteers got in front of their usernames was highly desirable,  and it these moderators something in return for the help they provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members  will likely offer to volunteer to help out in the community, whether it  be in through moderation, frequent engagement, or helping to create and  host events. Let them! Find ways to let the most dedicated community  members lead, create content, and provide value to other members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating, running and growing a Minecraft server for three and a half  years taught me a lot about community. I could probably write a post  two-to-three times longer than this one if I were to include everything,  but I’ll leave you with these four points that you can apply to your  own community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give community members the ability to earn social status and capital within the community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Truly  understand who your different members are, what value looks like to  them in the community, and find ways to provide that value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create  engagement. As your community grows, members should create engagement  among themselves, but you can always create points of engagement to help  encourage it, especially in the early days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let your  most active and dedicated members contribute back to the community,  through moderation, events, and engagement creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After reading an excellent post by Eugene Wei about Status as a Service earlier this week, I found myself thinking about my past experiences with community and status, and how those experiences could be applied to the communities I was working with today. I set out to write a fairly quick overview, but as you can see below I ended up with something a big longer. Strap in for story time!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting on Launching Modagrate</title><link href="https://macredd.in/reflecting-on-launching-modagrate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting on Launching Modagrate" /><published>2019-03-16T15:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T15:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://macredd.in/reflecting-on-launching-modagrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://macredd.in/reflecting-on-launching-modagrate">&lt;p&gt;I launched my first side project of 2019 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://modagrate.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Modagrate&lt;/a&gt;), with my friend Erik 21 days ago, on Feburary 22nd. As of writing this post we haven’t signed up a single paying user and are still struggling to decide what Modagrate should be. I’m writing this to outline the process we took in building and launching Modagrate, while trying to identify what we could have done better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline-of-the-modagrate-launch&quot;&gt;Timeline of the Modagrate launch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan 13&lt;/strong&gt; - A &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/1082223843870007297?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweet from Pieter Levels&lt;/a&gt; inspires the idea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan 16&lt;/strong&gt; - We decide to start building, decide on the name Modagrate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb 22&lt;/strong&gt; - Soft launched&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb 27&lt;/strong&gt; - Full launch (including posting on ProductHunt)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-we-do-on-launch-day&quot;&gt;What did we do on launch day?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/modagrate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ProductHunt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tweeted a bunch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Posted in various Slack and Telegram groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launched an improved version of the homepage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sat back and waited for success to happen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Febuary 26th I was incredibly excited, thinking about how many views and sign ups (including paid!) we were going to get. ProductHunt was all we needed to drive traffic and growth and properly launch Modagrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not have been more wrong. Like a lot of indie makers, I believed that tweeting our launch and sticking it on ProductHunt would be a silver bullet to our first customers and instant success. I assumed we could follow in the footsteps of already successful makers. But that only works if you already have a successful track record and a following due to those previous successes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d committed the cardinal sin - building without validating. We’d assumed that a tweet from Pieter Levels was enough validation that there was a market for our product - all we had to do was build it, and the rest would sort itself out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;launch-day-results&quot;&gt;Launch day results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It’s been about a day since &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Modagrate?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Modagrate&lt;/a&gt; was launched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProductHunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ProductHunt&lt;/a&gt;, so here are some stats!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;👍 50 upvotes&lt;br /&gt;👀 1,028 unique page views&lt;br /&gt;👥 17 sign ups (all free plan)&lt;br /&gt;🛡 199 auto moderation actions processed&lt;br /&gt;💬 4 live chats&lt;br /&gt;🐛 3 user reported bugs fixed&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mac (@TheTeaGuns) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheTeaGuns/status/1101164632419508224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 28, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of writing, we’ve had roughly another 500 unique page views, 8 sign ups (25 total, all free plan), and about 300 auto moderation actions. Definitely not the instant success we’d gotten caught up in believing it would be! We did get tons of support from fellow makers, but as I mention below, that doesn’t neccesarily translate to sign ups or success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-would-i-have-done-differently&quot;&gt;What would I have done differently?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, the biggest thing we failed to do was validate and build Modagrate with early customers and feedback. Luckily we only spent a few weeks building, so it isn’t a huge amount of time wasted. Can you imagine if we’d silently worked on Modagrate for 6 to 12 months before launching it publically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time around I’ll be reaching out to potential customers for feedback and input before and while building as well as launching sooner with a more minimal MVP. Even though it can be incredibly stressful and scary to put your ideas and projects out into the world for feedback it is definitely better to get negative feedback earlier rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with building openly in maker communities like &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmakerlog.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MakerLog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wip.chat&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WIP&lt;/a&gt; is that they can give a false sense of audience for your project. In Modagrate’s case, it was incredibly awesome to see other makers liking and supporting our progress updates, but at the end of the day they weren’t the target audience for Modagrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my next project will also be something a bit simpler. Content moderation is a huge, messy beast and I’m not sure Erik and I were equipped to properly tackle it in just a few weeks of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next-for-modagrate&quot;&gt;What’s next for Modagrate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a lot of ideas (integrations for starters, to allow people to access our moderation tools without having to integrate with an API) for what to do with Modagrate, so we’ll be spending some time reaching out to possible users and figuring out what direction makes sense both for us and those who could benefit from using Modagrate. We’re definitely not giving up just because we haven’t gotten any paying users yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still incredibly proud of what Erik and I were able to build in such a short time. The Modagrate launch wasn’t a failure, it was a learning experience and everything we’ve learned will be applied both to the future of Modagrate and any other projects we build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I launched my first side project of 2019 (Modagrate), with my friend Erik 21 days ago, on Feburary 22nd. As of writing this post we haven’t signed up a single paying user and are still struggling to decide what Modagrate should be. I’m writing this to outline the process we took in building and launching Modagrate, while trying to identify what we could have done better.</summary></entry></feed>